<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-23T21:39:48-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">a space for Rumination x Adventure</title><subtitle>I’ve put off writing this blog for years.  Because I've been stressing over making myself sound like I know my stuff. But I'm not perfect. I'm trialing through life, just as everybody else is.  And I’m trying to embrace this by  finally just doing what I’ve been wanting to do:  processing and sharing my thoughts through written words, unfiltered.  </subtitle><entry><title type="html">There’s so much good</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2020/03/23/theres-good.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="There's so much good" /><published>2020-03-23T01:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-23T01:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2020/03/23/theres-good</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2020/03/23/theres-good.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been protecting myself by not checking the news. I know there’s a lot of not so good things happening due to the coronavirus, and I think the magnitude of it all is greater than I comprehend right now. However, for my own mental health, I’ve been doing my own thing at home. Newsletters from people I admire and respect, Instagram, Twitter, Facebook and occasionally the local Chinese news have been my news source, which I check 1-2 times a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that I’ve surrounded myself with people who are serving others and amplifying the incredible people around the world who are serving others. With that, I’m still filled with hope and positivity from all the positive activities I’m virtually surrounded by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;people are connecting with others. we’re spending time with families, finding ways to connect with friends, learning to check in on people we know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communities are stepping up. in my neighborhood, people are offering to help older people purchase goods, share information about what’s still available where, share resources and offer services for those who are in need.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;music. dnice’s homeschool (aka club quarantine). singers’ free concerts on Insta.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;food. chefs are cooking in their homes and sharing the experience and lessons with others. many chefs and organizations are offering free meals to the community. schools are offering free meals for children and families.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;love for farmers. so many people are finding ways to support their local farmers directly. farmers are still farming. they’re literally the heart and blood of our food system, bless them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with so many people off roads, not traveling in planes, not outside (and littering), our air is cleaner. waters are cleaner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;downtime. we’re conditioned to feel like we have to always be busy, doing something. and i think this is an important time to give ourselves a break, relax, take care of ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;people are caring for personal health. exercising. cooking for themselves. reading. journaling. spending time with others. dancing. singing. and so much more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more and more attention, respect, and gratitude for all our service workers and how integral they are to our daily lives. the number of funds and donations to support those impacted by the pandemic is on the up and up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;heathcare providers. massive gratitude to them and all they do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ponderings" /><summary type="html">I’ve been protecting myself by not checking the news. I know there’s a lot of not so good things happening due to the coronavirus, and I think the magnitude of it all is greater than I comprehend right now. However, for my own mental health, I’ve been doing my own thing at home. Newsletters from people I admire and respect, Instagram, Twitter, Facebook and occasionally the local Chinese news have been my news source, which I check 1-2 times a day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just in time for 2020.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/12/29/found-my-2020-light.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just in time for 2020." /><published>2019-12-29T01:05:25-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-29T01:05:25-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/12/29/found-my-2020-light</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/12/29/found-my-2020-light.html">&lt;p&gt;I found a much-needed light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 weeks. That’s the max I’ve been home before this break in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been so easy living on my own because I live the way I want, with no judgment. I’d like to say no fear, but I hit an all-time low this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being home these past 2 weeks have been hard though. I think I just discovered why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m obsessed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ava&quot;&gt;Ava DuVernay&lt;/a&gt; right now. She’s brilliantly creative and infuses her work with immense dedication, hard work, passion, and meaning in a way that few I know have. This, I can see from just being an observer: a follower of her Insta + tweets, a listener and reader of her interviews. She literally shines with authenticity. And she is incredibly kind. I feel it through her words and in the way she calls people out, the way she recognizes others, and through the stories she tells. She’s also deeply intentional with her actions and faithful with herself. She knows her potential, her power, and she revels in her queendom (she a queen, there’s no denying it). And having spent hours consuming as much as I can about her, I realized this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents’ actions and comments have chipped at the fortitude that I’ve spent building up for the past few years. What they say doesn’t bother me because they’re not important. What they want of me is not important to me right now. But what they imply and mean (that is, what I’m hearing) through their words hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear before I continue on. My parents love me deeply. I try to remember that, especially when I get upset with them or they get upset with me. They do what they do because they think it’s what’s good or best for me (in the context of their understanding of the world). Because ultimately, that’s what they want: the best for me, I know that. But what they want is not necessarily what I want. What they think is best for me is not necessarily what actually is best for me. And that’s where the friction has become detrimental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My dad called me on his break today to ask what I ate. He often checks in on whether I’ve eaten and what I’ve eaten, even when I’m at school. I said I cooked some veggies, pasta, and turnip cake. He seems to disregard what I said and told me that I need to eat food. Then, he made a side comment on how Mom didn’t do any grocery shopping. I called him out: Dad(!), the fridge isn’t empty. I’m not starving. I cooked food. Did you call me just to reprimand me for not eating when I did?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that he thinks I’m starving myself or not eating enough because I committed to eating a lot less meat recently. Reality: No, I’m not starving myself and I am eating enough (at least I think I am; I’m often satisfied and full after eating). I’ve learned to cook, feed, and take better care of myself this past year (and have done so for the past 4 years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time he implies I’m not feeding myself well, I hear &lt;strong&gt;I don’t know how to take care of myself&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have habits that are uncommon to the average person, but is v familiar for anyone who has committed to taking climate action in their personal lives. I bring my own bags to shop in bulk bins. I compost almost all my waste, recycle the rest, and rarely throw anything into the trash. I support local businesses and farmers. I ask questions about the ingredients in products I buy. I often opt for meatless dishes. I ask for food to be packed in my own reusable containers instead of disposable ones. I carry my own reusables everywhere I go. To name a few things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom has said multiple times: I worry that you won’t find a husband. The context of the situation is that I’m educating her about separating the trash, not taking a plastic bag at the store, or something related to individual environmental activism. My dad doesn’t have the balls to tell me this directly. He tells my brother who relays it to me: Dad says you’re never going to find a husband with your tote carrying, refusing to take take-out box, eco-friendly habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I don’t need a man to complete me. But to hear my parents say this, I think &lt;strong&gt;ya’ll don’t respect what I care about. What I care about doesn’t matter to you.&lt;/strong&gt; I also hear &lt;strong&gt;I, alone, am not valuable or worthy enough&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My mom loves clothes shopping. I don’t, but I join her when we’re home together cause I know it makes her happy. However, the things she says is getting on my nerves. She reminds me to dress up, especially when I go out. Let the boys see you. People will respect you more. I joke that I’m already beautiful inside and out. I don’t need to dress up to prove that. She always responds: yes, but other people don’t know that. She may have some point there, but she’s been bringing this up for the past 3(?) years now. It doesn’t work, can she not stop? Of course parents don’t…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time, I get the feeling that &lt;strong&gt;my style isn’t good enough. My comfort is not important. I’m not beautiful enough.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My job search has been put on hold because tech companies are hiring product managers right now. Many companies that I’m interested in are not going to wait six months for me to graduate. But my lack of progress has my parents worrying. My mom keeps asking my brother (a software developer at a fintech) to help me find a job. She also takes advantage to ask my brother to introduce me to boys, as if my brother knows what kind of people I like…I don’t think he does. Although my brother is in the tech space, I don’t think he has much influence when it comes to referring product managers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fyi, I’m not stressed or worried about my job prospects. I believe in my potential and abilities. And I have faith that I’ll find a job when it’s right for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to hear my mom make this request behind my back (she’s done this when I wasn’t around according to my brother) and in front of me on multiple occasions. I know she has a habit of repeating herself. Plus, she raised us, constantly reminding us to help and love each other. I know she means well, but I wonder &lt;strong&gt;does she not have faith in me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more instances, but I’m not here to complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to say that I hear them loud and clear. And I feel like they’re telling me I’m not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely don’t think they mean that. Their actions and words are a product of culture, community, being a parent, and many factors. But their actions make me feel this way, and I need to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve let a lot of fear, antagonism, and self-doubt drive me away from what I’ve needed and wanted this year. One commitment I’ve made for 2020 and beyond is &lt;strong&gt;to not be in my own way&lt;/strong&gt;. I am going to channel the fear, antagonism, and self-doubt to fuel myself. To speak up about what’s not right around and with me. To build new and stronger relationships, environments, and communities for myself and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that, I’m going to have a talk with my parents about their actions and words, how they’ve made me feel, how I’d like them to change their tones and messages regarding these topics, what my values are and what I want, and ask them for their support for me as I am and who I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m nervous to have this conversation. I don’t know if my Chinese is good enough to communicate all this. I’m not sure how they will take it, or how I will respond and facilitate the discussion so it’s productive for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gotta do this though. For myself. And I’m committed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ponderings" /><summary type="html">I found a much-needed light.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My gift giving philosophy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/12/20/my-gift-giving-philosophy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My gift giving philosophy" /><published>2019-12-20T01:05:25-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-20T01:05:25-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/12/20/my-gift-giving-philosophy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/12/20/my-gift-giving-philosophy.html">&lt;p&gt;A friend asked me what I want. My mom asked me what I want. For the holidays. For my upcoming birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I say? Don’t buy me anything. Spend time with me. Care for me. Be my friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;unpacking-my-thoughts-on-receiving-gifts&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unpacking my thoughts on receiving gifts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three major factors to my thoughts on gifts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I value relationships the most in my life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I live a pretty minimalist lifestyle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I care about the environment, and the environment currently isn’t doing too hot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;minimalism&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I own what I need. I don’t want a bunch of crap lying around my place that I won’t use cause it collects dust, makes cleaning more time-consuming, and takes up unnecessary space in the limited luggages I have when I move around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;environment&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I need something, I’ll buy it myself. I know what companies I like and support. I can also do the research to find companies with values that most closely align with mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I need (materialistically) is often very practical: toothpaste, pads (I’m still working getting that DivaCup in me), floss, fresh/local/organic/seasonal/non-GMO foods, body wash, shampoo. I’m not going to ask someone to buy that for me; I can do that myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What upsets me most is when someone gives me something that I don’t need or is from a company that I don’t support. Because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now I have something that I won’t ever use just sitting in my home, taking up space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I most likely won’t be re-gifting this item. When I gift things, it always has a hint of me in it. Oftentimes, that means there’s an environmental element to it. So, if something is made of something I personally wouldn’t use, I won’t give that to someone else. That just violates the principles I live by.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t like waste, so I’m not going to throw the item away…yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: Someone once gave me a Lush body lotion Charity Pot, saying it’s fair trade. In my head, I’m like, “Yea, but it’s also made of ingredients that I would never put on my body, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ewg.org/skindeep/products/818541-Lush_Body_Lotion_Charity_Pot&quot;&gt;fragrance&lt;/a&gt;.” Those fragrances add up; I walked into a Lush store a last year, and literally walked back out because those smells gave me a headache. Idk what they put into their ingredient “fragrance” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.madesafe.org/science/hazard-list/fragrance&quot;&gt;which is the problem&lt;/a&gt;: the ingredient “fragrance” can be made up of many different chemicals that don’t have to be disclosed to consumers, which is questionable. What’s in it? Our bodies absorb about 60% of whatever we put on it (which enters our bloodstream), so let me know everything that’s in the product that I’m putting on my body). I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why this upsets me is: now I have the burden of figuring out what to do with this pot of lotion that I won’t ever use. FYI, it’s been sitting on my bathroom counter for a year now… Also, Lush, as a company, is doing something (which counts), but they can do a whole lot more towards environmental and health stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone may counter: but it’s the thought that counts. I will say sometimes it does; context matters though. Lotion is the safest present one can give another person. It’s like giving someone chocolates; you most likely can’t go wrong with it (except with one of my friends who doesn’t like chocolate and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.100daysofrealfood.com/food-babe-investigates-death-by-chocolate/&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;). So, was there real thought put into it? Sure, the person tried to give me something that aligned with my values, but the person fell very short. I give the person some credit though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I counter: giving gifts should be a happy occasion. I think the whole point of gift giving is to make the receivee happy, and as a result, when the receivee is happy, the gifter feels good that they did something nice for someone. In this case, I was much more annoyed than I was happy. I didn’t share any of these thoughts to the gifter. That wouldn’t have been nice, but these are the thoughts that ran through my mind when it happened and still run through my mind when people ask me what I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;relationships&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationships&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes me happy is when I know I have friends and family I can go to when I’m bored, confused, sad, upset, frustrated, angry, content, silly, happy, excited, curious; basically, all the time. Life is more fun when I live it with people I care about and people who care about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I ask for from people is to care. To be my friend, to be my family. To support me when I need it. To go on adventures with me. To want to spend time with me and make it happen (not just talk about it). To know that others are thinking of me, that I’m not alone. To care about the things I care about and respect that. (When people tell me they changed a habit to better care for the environment, that alone literally makes my day and reminds me that what I do matters. That alone is a gift.) That’s all I ask for, and that’s all I want from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big ask, so save your money. Don’t buy me anything. You can’t buy happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;practice-just-being-a-better-friend-and-person-to-others-for-me-thats-what-matters-to-me-and-thats-whatll-make-me-happy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice just being a better friend and person to others for me. That’s what matters to me, and that’s what’ll make me happy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S.&lt;/strong&gt; I wouldn’t mind having a friend like Oprah Winfrey though. She gifts avocadoes from her backyard. Homegrown fruits and veggies cared with love are the bestest foods one can eat.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">A friend asked me what I want. My mom asked me what I want. For the holidays. For my upcoming birthday.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thanks, bro.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/09/16/bro-moment1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanks, bro." /><published>2019-09-16T08:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T08:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/09/16/bro-moment1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/09/16/bro-moment1.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky to have my brother. I’m lucky that we have a good relationship. And I’m lucky to have a brother who makes me laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother is a software engineer. So, he understands when I texted him in need of some sympathy that I had spent wayyyy too long to discover I misplaced a block of code outside a while loop for my homework. Our conversation continued like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B (for bro): Lol&lt;br /&gt;
B: Don’t you love to code? :’)&lt;br /&gt;
M: no, this is why i don’t sleep&lt;br /&gt;
M: this is why i dream about my hw&lt;br /&gt;
B: Isn’t it awesome?&lt;br /&gt;
B: Academia&lt;br /&gt;
B: Dream about hw problems&lt;br /&gt;
M: thats another level of dreaming… i have transcended, lol. i have yet to dream about the solutions to my hw problems.&lt;br /&gt;
B: Wow, if you do that&lt;br /&gt;
B: You will literally have transcended&lt;br /&gt;
B: Get to the stage of dreaming about the solutions to your hw problems!!&lt;br /&gt;
M: I like you, you make me laugh (I literally burst out laughing at those last few texts)&lt;br /&gt;
B: thank u&lt;br /&gt;
B: I praise myself as well&lt;br /&gt;
M: what do you praise yourself for?&lt;br /&gt;
B: For being me (insert hand peace sign)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends think I’m too positive sometimes. And I think, how can I be negative when I have a brother like this one? One who allows me to complain but also twists it into a positive light (to be fair, he really likes what he does). One who can joke about things so nonchalantly. One who can easily dissipate my pent up emotions. I was real frustrated and upset when I texted him, and immediately after this text chain, I was okay again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thankful and grateful to have someone like my bro in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ponderings" /><summary type="html">I’m lucky to have my brother. I’m lucky that we have a good relationship. And I’m lucky to have a brother who makes me laugh.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekend in Chicago.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/09/16/19-chicago.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekend in Chicago." /><published>2019-09-16T01:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T01:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/09/16/19-chicago</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/09/16/19-chicago.html">&lt;p&gt;My friends (they’re also my roomies this year) roped me into going to Chicago with them our first weekend of the school year (Labor Day weekend). Roped as in one friend asked me if I wanted to go to Chicago this weekend. My instinctive response was, “No, I can’t. I have a lot of work to do.” Then, I thought about it for two minutes. Concluded that my excuse was BS. I always have a lot of work to do. And was like, “Okay, let’s do it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rented a car and had a hot girls summer road trip. Lots of singing in the car and laughs. It was a really good relaxing weekend + a good start to our final year in college. My friends have both been to Chicago, so I let them take the reins in deciding what to do. My only two criteria: Chicago deep dish pizza and farmers’ market on the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m usually the one who has to decide (has to because no one else will make a decision) and make plans for trips, so it was uber sweet to not think about any of that and just follow where my friends take me. The most memorable moments were the food, the city views, and the dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food worth mentioning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cqbakery.com/menu/&quot;&gt;Chiu Qwon Bakery&lt;/a&gt; – authentic Chinese pastries and at affordable prices. What rubbish to go to a cafe in downtown Chicago and pay $5 for a muffin… I got me a whole box to share with my friends and satiate my Chinese sweet cravings. It was also nice to speak Cantonese with someone (it’s interesting how being able to communicate in a familiar tongue can feel so comforting).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saintsalpchicago.com/&quot;&gt;Saint’s Alp Teahouse&lt;/a&gt; – authentic Chinese cafe food. Chinese food is a few cuisines that serves whole plates of vegetables instead of a miniscule incorporation of veggies. I got me a fix of bubble milk tea and a plate of A choy. Reminds me of weekend trips to Chinatown with my mom when I was little. We’d stop by a Chinese cafe for brunch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creperianuevoleon.com/index.html#foodline&quot;&gt;Creperia Nuevo Leon&lt;/a&gt; – authentic Mexican food. I’m not very familiar with Mexican food, so when I looked at the menu at this place, I was like ehh. There’s the usual bell peppers, cheese, black beans, rice, and tortilla. But man, when the dish came out, I was soo excited. It was freaking delicious. I don’t remember what the name of the dish I ordered is, but I got the vegetarian option that had cheese, corn, beans, rice, and corn tortilla. Changed my opinion of Mexican food and made me realize I’ve never had authentic Mexican food before. The restaurant is well decorated and has good local vibes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just fyi, I don’t prefer American food, and I often aim to find authentic ethnic cuisines when going out to eat. We ate at a few American restaurants which was way pricey for the quality of food and how hungry I was after eating. Both the Chinese and Mexican meals cost ~$15 each including tax and tip, and I was fully satiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I did get deep dish pizza at Lou Malnati’s, but I was not impressed. I feel like the ones I’ve had in the Bay Area and St. Louis are better than what I had there…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City views:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wendella river boat tour of the city was beautiful. We were on the boat in the transition from day to sunset, so we got views of the city lights. Also, the historical/architectural lessons were interesting. Went on the 40 minutes one vs. 75 because we wanted to save money. Tbh though, 40 minutes was perfect. Any longer and we would have been bored and wondering when we’d get off the boat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The architecture of buildings is magnificient. I’m incredibly impressed by the human capacity to think and make these designs come to life. I wish they were for more important use cases though instead of expensive hotels and shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dancing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slipperyslopechicago.com/&quot;&gt;Slippery Slope&lt;/a&gt; – Friday night was lit. They played black people music, and the people there could dance. Crowded and good vibes. One of my friends can really feel the music and dance, and she went all out. She’s actually the one who inspired me to learn to dance. We always take dance breaks from work at our apartment and have lots of fun. It was so fun we went back on Sunday, but that was sad. Cause they were playing EDM and there was definitely not the same crowd there. I literally saw 6 people walk in and walk back out, disappointed at the music. We left too after a few minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The socioeconomic disparity was very prominent. We lived about a 20 minute public transportation trip from downtown, so we walked through various neighborhoods. One moment that remains in memory is when we were on the train, heading to the farmers’ market. A homeless man asked for people’s attention and said he didn’t want to bother us but he was really hungry. He asked if anyone had any water, leftover food, or spare change so he could get food. That tore my heart. Of all times, I literally had no water or food on me. I regretted eating my snack the day before, because then I could have given that to him. I just stood there feeling bad and didn’t respond. There were many people on streets of downtown Chicago asking for food and saying they were hungry that day, but their requests didn’t hit me as much as this man’s. From him, it just felt so much more genuine and deeper, which made me actually rummage through my bag and think about what I could offer him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think back on it, I should have asked him to follow my friend and I to our stop and buy him some food. I have rule that I won’t give homeless people cash because I don’t know what they’ll spend it on, and I don’t approve of eating at fast food restaurants or buying junk food at convenience stores. This is me imposing my own personal habits on others. However, I believe that no one should be without water or food, especially in a place where there is so much food around. (I can see that this belief is contradictory to what my actions were, which is why I wished I had behaved differently.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="adventures" /><summary type="html">My friends (they’re also my roomies this year) roped me into going to Chicago with them our first weekend of the school year (Labor Day weekend). Roped as in one friend asked me if I wanted to go to Chicago this weekend. My instinctive response was, “No, I can’t. I have a lot of work to do.” Then, I thought about it for two minutes. Concluded that my excuse was BS. I always have a lot of work to do. And was like, “Okay, let’s do it!”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Austin to-do list.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/08/25/what-to-do-austin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Austin to-do list." /><published>2019-08-25T01:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-25T01:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/08/25/what-to-do-austin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/08/25/what-to-do-austin.html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, last week in Austin over. I’ve had frustrations as is normal with all new challenging experiences, but it was overall a really really good experience (I say this with a big smile) because I’ve learned so much more than I could have imagined. About what I like and don’t like, what I want and don’t want in my life, professionally and personally. I’m also so much more comfortable and happy with who I am. Best summer I’ve had yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lived in Austin for 3 months this summer. And based on my experiences, here are some recs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can’t miss Lady Bird Lake; it’s the Colorado River that runs through Austin where people kayak and stand-up paddleboard. You can also run, walk, bike, and scooter along it. Depending on where you are, you can get great views of downtown Austin’s skyline. It’s hard to enjoy this in late summer though when it’s really hot and sunny.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love supporting local and buying fresh local organic seasonal product, so I visited the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainablefoodcenter.org/programs/sfc-farmers-market&quot;&gt;downtown farmers’ market&lt;/a&gt; every weekend. It’s small compared to ones from my hometown in the East Bay Area, but it had everything I needed. This particular farmers’ market has free samples of many vendors’ products; a fantastic french bakery stall; local jewelers; and food stalls (which I didn’t try but looked good!), so visit if you can.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barton Springs Pool is a popular place. There’s swimming in water sourced from nearby natural springs; it’s cool water year round, no matter how hot it gets. In the heat of summertime, this is perfect activity. You have to pay to get in, but if you walk downhill from the paid/gated area, there’s a free area where lots of people and dogs play.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capitol building is free for all and cool to see. It’s where all state legistlative proceedings take place, so you see where these governmental processes occur.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cheerupcharlies.com/&quot;&gt;Cheer Up Charlies&lt;/a&gt;, go there for drinks + with good company. They’ve got good cocktails and good vibes. Fantastic drag shows.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you like hipster vibes, check out East Austin for food, coffee shops, and bars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/whenwherewhataustin/&quot;&gt;instagram (When Where What Austin)&lt;/a&gt; came in clutch a few times. Thanks to them, my friends and I attended some cool art shows + free/discounted drinks + food events, good times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://austin.violetcrown.com/&quot;&gt;Violet Crown&lt;/a&gt; provides a very comfortable, clean, boutique theatre experience. Also, on 2nd street which looks pretty at night when all the lights wrapped around the trees are lit up. They show films, not blockbuster movies. Affordable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spiderhouseatx.com/&quot;&gt;Spiderhouse&lt;/a&gt; has several food trucks and outdoor area to eat and chat with company. It’s got quirky decor that is like super Austin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookpeople.com/&quot;&gt;BookPeople&lt;/a&gt; is a local bookstore with LOTS of books. Booklovers and appreciaters, come here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’ve got any interest in gokarting, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.circuitoftheamericas.com/&quot;&gt;Circuit of the Americas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://austincontainerbar.com/&quot;&gt;The Container Bar&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t go here. They had a really long line that my friends + I didn’t really care to wait for. But looks like fun place. If you want nightlife, checkout Red River and Rainey area; they’ve gotchu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cooked a lot this summer because it’s affordable and I can cook nutritious dishes to my own liking. I also eat a plant-based diet, so very little to no meat. So, of the limited number of places and dishes I’ve tried, here are food places I would go back to eat again (and for some, actually did go back again):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chilantrobbq.com/&quot;&gt;Chi’lantro&lt;/a&gt; – I went to their food truck near my office. It’s Chipotle-style build your own, but with a Korean flair. Yummy, filling meal on cheaper end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xianfresh.com&quot;&gt;Xian Sushi and Noodle&lt;/a&gt; – They specialize in hand-pulled noodles. Delicious, satisfied Asian food cravings, and also on cheaper end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arpeggiogrill.com/&quot;&gt;Arpeggio Grill&lt;/a&gt; – They make very aromatic rice. Highly recommend the grilled fish plate; well seasoned and flavorful fish + aromatic rice. Meats were well seasoned; although, my parents said their meats were too salty for them. I got the vegetarian platter, which was decent but not fantastic. Affordable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wuchowaustin.com/&quot;&gt;Wu Chow&lt;/a&gt; – My frugal ass wouldn’t go back here on my own. They’ve got very delicious Chinese flavors though, pretty authentic (coming from a Chinese person)! Love that they’re farm-to-table, supporting local farms and serving fresh, local, organic, seasonal foods. High-end, classy feel. Pricey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracruzallnatural.com/&quot;&gt;Veracruz All Natural&lt;/a&gt; – I didn’t eat here myself, never got a chance. However, if I had a choice, I would have come here for tacos because I appreciate their philosophy of using fresh, natural ingredients and like that they serve authentic Mexican food. I’m not familiar with authentic Mexican food flavors, but they seem legit to me. I could have been tricked though. However, 2 friends this summer tried their food, and they had raving reviews, so this place makes it on my list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.easytigerusa.com/&quot;&gt;Easy Tiger&lt;/a&gt; – I also didn’t eat here myself, but I’ve heard fantastic reviews about this place. My hobbyist breadmaker friends say their breads are freaking delicious. Good happy hour place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="adventures" /><summary type="html">Wow, last week in Austin over. I’ve had frustrations as is normal with all new challenging experiences, but it was overall a really really good experience (I say this with a big smile) because I’ve learned so much more than I could have imagined. About what I like and don’t like, what I want and don’t want in my life, professionally and personally. I’m also so much more comfortable and happy with who I am. Best summer I’ve had yet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Local makes me happy.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/08/11/local-makes-me-happy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Local makes me happy." /><published>2019-08-11T01:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-11T01:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/08/11/local-makes-me-happy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/08/11/local-makes-me-happy.html">&lt;p&gt;I just got back from a trip to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheatsville.coop/&quot;&gt;Wheatsville Food Co-op&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m super happy right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason for trip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cooked a bulk pot of pink rice that I got from Wheatsville a week ago when it was on sale (#trynewfoodwhenitsonsale). I overestimated and made like 10 meals’ worth of rice, when I was aiming for 4-5. I store the rice in fridge, which is fine except the rice dries out. So, to compensate for the dryness, I know I need to cook saucy veggies. So my goal of this trip was to get a jar of sauce under $5, probably a curry-like sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for why I’m super happy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I slept in til 10:30am. Although I did sleep at 2am-ish, I felt like I finally got the sleep I needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cointern introduced me to the field of healthcare technology and I’ve been starting to read and learn about the industry through the lens of disruptive innovation. I’m in the state where I just found a new interest and am super excited about understanding it. There’s so many tabs on my computer right now, and I just requested about 10 books from my college to read (upon my return in 2 weeks!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like my outfit today, and I feel good in it. It’s just a simple colorful dress, my Birkenstocks, + my trusty grocery tote bag.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s sunny outside, so that raised my vitamin D levels, as I made my bus adventure over to Wheatsville.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wheatsville has a compost bin. I collect my compost until I make a trip to a grocery store with composting or my compost containers are all full, so I finally got to empty my containers after 2 weeks! People have noted that my collection of compost and disposal process seems very extra; call it what you will. I am proud to divert ~95% of my waste from the landfill. Composting ensures my food scraps get recycled into nutrients for soil. Landfilling waste ensures more methane is released into the atmosphere, thereby worsening climate change. (Landfills are so compact with trash that anaerobic decomposition occurs, which produces methane as a byproduct. Methane, btw, is 34x worse than CO2 in warming effect.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wheatsville has free food samples. I love food, and I love good free food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wheatsville also had organic peaches on sale: $1.99/lb. A month or two ago, it was $2.49/lb at Whole Foods (and that was considered on sale). These peaches were pretty soft and ripe, so I’m guessing it’s due to an abundant supply. Regardless, #yayseasonalfruits and yay for on sale organic produce. I had a realization yesterday. I’ve been craving sweets for the past two weeks, and have turned towards eating a lots of granola bars at work, which has a bunch of added sugar. Yesterday, I went to the farmers’ market and got a locally grown organic korean melon for $2! (Has like 6-ish servings worth?) A korean melon, as described to me and I can now confirm having ate it, is a fruit like a watermelon but with a firmer texture like an apple. (The skin can also be eaten, it tastes fine to me!) Anyways, I realized I haven’t eaten real fruit in like 2 weeks. In the beginning of my summer, I would eat a bunch of fruits (e.g. blueberries, raspberries, strawberries, peaches, nectarines, pluots) to satisfy my sweet tooth and ate nothing with added sugars for a whole month. Then that streak broke down. Me not buying fruits was partially 1) Austin farmers’ markets don’t have many fruit offerings, and 0 that are organic 2) I didn’t want to buy fruits from Whole Foods cause I don’t want to support Amazon and 3) not needing to go to grocery stores to buy anything else. After eating my korean melon, I realized that I need more real fresh fruit in my diet (&lt;a href=&quot;https://foodrevolution.org/blog/sugar-substitutes/&quot;&gt;real fruit &amp;gt; sugary sweets&lt;/a&gt;). So I was real happy to bought a bunch of peaches on sale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grocery shopping is my favorite type of shopping, so just being in a grocery store lifted my mood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found a coconut curry sauce within my budget. Plus, it’s in a reusable glass jar!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wheatsville is a special place; it embodies and practices environmental and social stewardship in ways I wish more grocery stores would do. Wherever I live, I want to have a Wheatville-like grocery store near me. If there isn’t one, I want to start one.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They offer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eoproducts.com/&quot;&gt;EO hand sanitizer&lt;/a&gt; instead of convetional brands like Purcell.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They offer compostable bags over plastic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They support and stock a lot of local brands and label them. Supporting local is important in boosting the local economy. Buying local means more money you spend remains in your community because local businesses tend to support local vendors as well, contributing towards increasing more local jobs and supporting local distribution and processing systems.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They use non-plastic (paper) sample cups.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They have a bulk section which is where I get all my grains and legumes. I love that they have bulk peanut butter.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They have weekly sales that make shopping local and organic more affordable. They also have what basic staples priced at affordable price points.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their bakery makes their pastries and breads look so freaking delicious and wholesome.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their housemade desserts, pastries, and breads are made with unenriched and unbleached flours (read about what’s problematic with enriched and bleached flour &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodbabe.com/ingredients-to-avoid/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). They’re also not filled with a ton of additives, preservatives, and added sugars, as I see in Whole Foods’ baked goods.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They support local non-profits by offering customers to round up their total to nearest dollar to donate to a different non-profit each month.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They ask me if I want my receipt. I always refuse, and they don’t print it out. Unlike Whole Foods, where even if I say no, it’s printed out and thrown into the trash; what a freaking waste. I don’t take receipts because 1) I don’t need it. If I do, I just take photo of the computer screen. 2) 94% of receipts are lined with BPA and BPS, which are endocrine disruptors. (Read more about impact of receipts &lt;a href=&quot;https://greenamerica.org/report-STS&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) I don’t know if Wheatsville’s receipts are lined with BPA or not, cause I’ve never taken one.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It holds so many brands that I love and also has introduced me to brands I was previously unfamiliar with that are very mindful of their environmental and social impact. I discovered the brand &lt;a href=&quot;https://fitppl.com/&quot;&gt;fitppl&lt;/a&gt; today because they were offering samples. I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truvani.com/&quot;&gt;Truvani’s plant-based protein&lt;/a&gt;, which I mix with water and drink a few times a week. I like Truvani because it’s founded by a food blogger I follow. She taught me a lot about how the food industry is tricking consumers in thinking their food is “healthy”. Her company is focused on transparency and clean ingredients, but there’s more a company can do. fitppl does this, I absolutely love their initiative more. Their site talks about building healthy soil and promoting biodiversity through sourcing their ingredients. They are thoughtful of their waste output and their product reflects their initiative to reduce their waste as much as possible. Their ingredients are certified organic and they source locally in Texas as much as possible (they’re an Austin-based company). They raise awareness about plastic pollution and actively participate in trash cleanups in the community. (Yesssss, you rock fitppl!)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There are definitely more reasons why I love Wheatsville and local independent grocery stores, but these are the reasons that were on the top of my mind today.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I came back to make lunch, and very pleased with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mayakaimal.com/product/prod-rs-coconutcurry/&quot;&gt;Goan curry by Maya Kaimal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am also very proud of how far I’ve come with cooking. My palate and cooking skills have changed. I make veggie stir fries that have satisfied my appetite and taste buds. (Btw, I learned how to steam beet, and am uber proud that I can cook beets now.) Next goal is to learn how to make my own sauces and I’ll be set to make any dish incredibly tasty (to me, at least).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s what Wheatsville stands for, my enjoyment and appreciation of their values and practices, and this realization during my experience in their store today that made me happy, and I just had to share. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">I just got back from a trip to Wheatsville Food Co-op, and I’m super happy right now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t ask me ‘How are you’.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/07/31/how-are-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't ask me 'How are you'." /><published>2019-07-31T01:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T01:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/07/31/how-are-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/07/31/how-are-you.html">&lt;p&gt;Note: This is a rant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of answer do you expect to hear from this? Do you actually care how I am? People have literally asked me this while smiling and walking away… I’m thinking, why did you waste your breath? You make yourself think you’re being nice by asking, but you’re really not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, at work, people will ask me how I am. I saw you yesterday. You know just as well as I do that we both woke up in the last hour or two, went through our morning routine, and came to work. There’s not much to my day so far, and I’m just ‘good’ or ‘okay’. (hahaha, those are my usual go-to answers. They hold validity though. If I’m feeling ‘good’ I say so. If I’m not feeling above average, then I go with ‘okay’.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I were actually doing bad, do you think asking me how I am will invite me to divulge the emotions and thoughts that consume my mind? Do you even want that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I’m looking really deep into this, but hey, it entertains me right now. All this is to say, I’m not about this common form of greeting. Just say hi, smile and let’s move on with our day. If you really care about me and want to know more, ask me a more specific question and ask follow up questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ponderings" /><summary type="html">Note: This is a rant.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A weekend trip to Houston.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/22/houston.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A weekend trip to Houston." /><published>2019-07-22T01:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-22T01:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/22/houston</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/22/houston.html">&lt;p&gt;A couple cointerns and I made a road trip to Houston this weekend. After work on Friday, we picked up our rental car and peaced out of Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this on drive back to Austin. Overall impression from our time here: a weekend is plenty of time to see Houston (we wouldn’t know what else to do if we had more time). Houston appears, from our visitor’s perspective, to be “big”, spread out, “quiet”, “suburban”, hot. (quotes are words my cointerns used) I think there are more gems to Houston that we didn’t see, but that’s alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opinion is based on our following adventures to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mala Sichuan Bistro&lt;/strong&gt; – disappointment. It didn’t satisfy my cravings for authentic quality Chinese food. It was definitely made by chinese people though. I was so excited for mapo tofu, but their sauce seemed way too oily and seemingly watered down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snowy Village&lt;/strong&gt; – classic Chinese/Asian dessert spot with shaved ice. Hella popping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbnb&lt;/strong&gt; – that was interesting. We entered the place to discover all the sheets and towels were used and noticably dirty by previous occupants. The host didn’t respond to our message until next morning. So we improvised and washed some of the towels and sheets in their washing machines with the remaining shampoo they had. We had clean towels to shower with in the morning, so it all worked out and we were satisfied with the host refunding us our first night’s stay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbanharvest.org/farmersmarkets/&quot;&gt;Urban East Side Farmers’ Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – I look forward to the farmers’ market every weekend, and I try to visit the local farmers’ market everywhere I go. There were lots of stands for produce, pastries, and food. I was most excited about some candied ginger and orange peels I got for my mom because she likes candied ginger. (packaged in reusable glass jar was bonus) I also got groceries for the week, lol. Some prices were cheaper than Austin and I needed groceries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blacksmith&lt;/strong&gt; – cointerns wanted coffee. Place had good vibes. I’m not much of a coffee drinker so I didn’t care too much for the place. According to my cointern who cares about coffee a whole lot more, he said the place gave him TJ Maxx level coffee feels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.menil.org/&quot;&gt;The Menil Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – I’m not a huge art appreciater. However, both my cointerns are. So it was a nice surprise to have spent 2.5 hours here. We looked at each piece of art, and I can appreciate art a little bit more now. I wouldn’t voluntarily choose to go see it on my own, but if I’m there, I wouldn’t mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Menil Bookstore&lt;/strong&gt; – Ehh, I didn’t care for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cy Twombly Gallery&lt;/strong&gt; – I found one piece I really liked there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andescafe.com/&quot;&gt;Andes Cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – This was my favorite part of the trip; food often holds a special part of my adventures. The staff was super welcoming and kind. I don’t eat South American food much (only a few times in my life), so this was a fantastic introduction to the cuisine (specifically, Venezuelan and Ecuadorean) and I’m intrigued to eat more now. Favorite dish was by far the cachapas; these Venezuelan sweet corn pancakes were flippin’ delicious. The cuisine is not very vegetarian friendly. I did try a little bit of meat to taste the flavors and got lots of seafood from the ceviche mixto. But I mostly ate and picked around the meat while my buddies ate the meat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rice University&lt;/strong&gt; – We walked around a little bit and hung out at the Skyspace (not necessary to see…its a ceiling with a square hole). It was very peaceful and lots of green trees and grass. The buildings are very simple, lots of brick in a non-intrusive kind of way. That’s as best I can describe it;I wasn’t impressed by the buildings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drove through &lt;strong&gt;Downtown&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Heights&lt;/strong&gt; area – downtown view from afar at night is cool to see. Being in downtown though, I felt so small being surrounded by such large buildings. The glass builidngs and lack of culture created a cold environment. We drove through for like 5  minutes and bounced. The Heights neighborhood was only a couple streets, but pleasant to drive through. We were there when most shops were about to close, so we didn’t bother walking around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agorahouston.com/&quot;&gt;Agora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – interesting cafe-like place. They have wine, beer, a greek frappuccino, and sweet and nice looking pastries. Good vibes to chat, work, read, write, anything I’d want to do in a cafe.
Prior to Agora, we stopped by a few cute small shops mext to it. Nice to browse.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bar hopping&lt;/strong&gt; – We were in Montrose area. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anvilhouston.com/&quot;&gt;Anvil Bar + Refuge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has some good cocktails. Otherwise, no good dance music (which is what I look for, specifically hip hop, rap, pop). Not good scene for people in early 20s, for sure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thai Stellar&lt;/strong&gt; – Prior to visiting NASA Johnson Space Center, we got food. It’s standard Thai cuisine, very cheap (you can get meal under $10). When they ask you for spice level, note that level 4 (what most my table got) was not spicy at all, for people who like and don’t mind spicy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rocket Park at NASA Johnson Center&lt;/strong&gt; – Seeing the rockets made me have a greater respect for the human mind. Literally, I cannot comprehend the inputs required to enable humans to send a person to outer space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bucc-ee’s&lt;/strong&gt; – This is like a Walmart gas station that is a unique experience in Texas. It just has lots of gas stations, car wash stations, huge store. So many people recommended seeing it, and we did. I was frustrated seeing all the plastic and single-use plastics available here. Because of my interests in sustainability, health, and nutrition, I was not impressed by the place. However, I do think it’s worth to stop by if it’s on your way to a destination though; interesting take on gas station.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was a good trip overall. Even though it was only a 48 hour trip, it felt like a really long time, like a whole week. Work seems so far away. I think the feeling that it was a long trip means I really lived in the present and was enjoying the moments. I’m still thinking about the cachapas and the sauce from the camarones (shrimp) we ordered; freaking delicious. I want more. :P&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="adventures" /><summary type="html">A couple cointerns and I made a road trip to Houston this weekend. After work on Friday, we picked up our rental car and peaced out of Austin.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smiling is magic.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/smiles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smiling is magic." /><published>2019-07-13T02:05:25-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T02:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/smiles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/smiles.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a good Saturday. I got a much-needed good night’s sleep, no alarm to wake me up. Put in a little workout in the morning and off to the farmers’ market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin is cool in that it has municipal composting. My apartment doesn’t have composting, but I can make a trip to my preferred grocery stores and compost my food scraps there. I collect my week’s compost in my freezer, and it was piling up, so I made a trip to Whole Foods to dispose of my compost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, my bro called me, which was a really nice surprise! We talked for an hour, where he filled me in on his first week at his new job (exciting)! We had a good sibling chat, while I enjoyed the views of families and individuals enjoying the park next to the downtown farmers’ market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a bus day today, aka I got a 24 hour bus pass to travel around Austin. This was mainly due to the very hot weather and my need to get to places faster than it would take me to walk to places. I’m not sure what was going on though, but so many people smiled at me today. I think it might be because I have a natural tendency to smile at people who I make eye contact with. And people’s natural instinct is to smile back. However, I noticed it a lot more today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made me feel extra good to be smiled at. If you’re curious as to why I have a natural tendency to smile a lot and to people, it’s because it feels good to be smiled at, and it makes others smile. When I was little, I liked people who smiled at me. And wanting others to like me, I practiced smiling at other people, genuinely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned here in Austin is that it’s nice to say ‘thank you’ to the bus drivers. It seems obvious but so few people do it. When I took my first bus trip in Austin, I saw a guy say ‘thank you’ to the bus driver when he got off. And in my head, I was like, “Wow, that’s so nice!” So I’ve been doing that too now. When I get off, I’ll look at the bus driver via their mirror, say thank you (and smile if I remember to, I’m not super conscious when I smile anymore), maybe wave, and get off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also say ‘hi’ to the bus driver and smile every time I get on. Today, every single bus driver smiled back and said ‘hi’ to me. It made me feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found an African fashion show to attend, and there, I made eye contact with this little girl. I smiled, and her face lit up, and she smiled back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hahaha, these aren’t really exciting stories, but as I am writing about them, it just makes me smile and feel good. There’s lots of positive energy that comes from this small exchange. I had more smile exchanges with vendors at the farmers’ market today, other attendees of the African fashion show, and people in my apartment building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I’m dedicating to being alone and getting a lot more content editing done for my app. I had a little too much excitement this week and need a break from fully engaging with people. And I have to say, this weekend is the best weekend I’ve had so far. It feels good to be alone, to do my own thing and have small moments of positivity with so many strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was more a brain dump and my day’s update, haha. The main takeaway though: smiling is magic, try it. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">Today was a good Saturday. I got a much-needed good night’s sleep, no alarm to wake me up. Put in a little workout in the morning and off to the farmers’ market.</summary></entry></feed>