<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-23T23:26:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">a space for Rumination x Adventure</title><subtitle>I’ve put off writing this blog for years.  Because I've been stressing over making myself sound like I know my stuff. But I'm not perfect. I'm trialing through life, just as everybody else is.  And I’m trying to embrace this by  finally just doing what I’ve been wanting to do:  practice processing my thoughts through written words, unfiltered.  </subtitle><entry><title type="html">A weekend trip to Houston.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/22/houston.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A weekend trip to Houston." /><published>2019-07-22T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-22T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/22/houston</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/22/houston.html">&lt;p&gt;A couple cointerns and I made a road trip to Houston this weekend. After work on Friday, we picked up our rental car and peaced out of Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this on drive back to Austin. Overall impression from our time here: a weekend is plenty of time to see Houston (we wouldn’t know what else to do if we had more time). Houston appears, from our visitor’s perspective, to be “big”, spread out, “quiet”, “suburban”, hot. (quotes are words my cointerns used) I think there are more gems to Houston that we didn’t see, but that’s alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opinion is based on our following adventures to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mala Sichuan Bistro&lt;/strong&gt; – disappointment. It didn’t satisfy my cravings for authentic quality Chinese food. It was definitely made by chinese people though. I was so excited for mapo tofu, but their sauce seemed way too oily and seemingly watered down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snowy Village&lt;/strong&gt; – classic Chinese/Asian dessert spot with shaved ice. Hella popping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbnb&lt;/strong&gt; – that was interesting. We entered the place to discover all the sheets and towels were used and noticably dirty by previous occupants. The host didn’t respond to our message until next morning. So we improvised and washed some of the towels and sheets in their washing machines with the remaining shampoo they had. We had clean towels to shower with in the morning, so it all worked out and we were satisfied with the host refunding us our first night’s stay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbanharvest.org/farmersmarkets/&quot;&gt;Urban East Side Farmers’ Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – I look forward to the farmers’ market every weekend, and I try to visit the local farmers’ market everywhere I go. There were lots of stands for produce, pastries, and food. I was most excited about some candied ginger and orange peels I got for my mom because she likes candied ginger. (packaged in reusable glass jar was bonus) I also got groceries for the week, lol. Some prices were cheaper than Austin and I needed groceries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blacksmith&lt;/strong&gt; – cointerns wanted coffee. Place had good vibes. I’m not much of a coffee drinker so I didn’t care too much for the place. According to my cointern who cares about coffee a whole lot more, he said the place gave him TJ Maxx level coffee feels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.menil.org/&quot;&gt;The Menil Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – I’m not a huge art appreciater. However, both my cointerns are. So it was a nice surprise to have spent 2.5 hours here. We looked at each piece of art, and I can appreciate art a little bit more now. I wouldn’t voluntarily choose to go see it on my own, but if I’m there, I wouldn’t mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Menil Bookstore&lt;/strong&gt; – Ehh, I didn’t care for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cy Twombly Gallery&lt;/strong&gt; – I found one piece I really liked there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://andescafe.com/&quot;&gt;Andes Cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – This was my favorite part of the trip; food is often holds a special part of my adventures. The staff was super welcoming and kind. I don’t eat South American food much (only a few times in my life), so this was a fantastic introduction to the cuisine (specifically, Venezuelan and Ecuadorean) and I’m intrigued to eat more now. Favorite dish was by far the cachapas; these Venezuelan sweet corn pancakes were flippin’ delicious. The cuisine is not very vegetarian friendly. I did try a little bit of meat to taste the flavors and got lots of seafood from the ceviche mixto. But I mostly ate and picked around the meat while my buddies ate the meat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rice University&lt;/strong&gt; – We walked around a little bit and hung out at the Skyspace (not necessary to see…its a ceiling with a square whole). It was very peaceful and lots of green trees and grass. The buildings are very simple, lots of brick in a non-intrusive kind of way. That’s as best I can describe it;I wasn’t impressed by the buildings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drove through &lt;strong&gt;Downtown&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Heights&lt;/strong&gt; area – downtown view from afar at night is cool to see. Being in downtown though, I felt so small being surrounded by such large buildings. The glass builidngs and lack of culture created a cold environment. We drove through for like 5  minutes and bounced. The Heights neighborhood was only a couple streets, but pleasant to drive through. We were there when most shops were about to close, so we didn’t bother walking around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agorahouston.com/&quot;&gt;Agora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – interesting cafe-like place. They have wine, beer, a greek frappuccino, and sweet and nice looking pastries. Good vibes to chat, work, read, write, anything I’d want to do in a cafe.
Prior to Agora, we stopped by a few cute small shops mext to it. Nice to browse.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bar hopping&lt;/strong&gt; – We were in Montrose area. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anvilhouston.com/&quot;&gt;Anvil Bar + Refuge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has some good cocktails. Otherwise, no good dance music (which is what I look for, specifically hip hop, rap, pop). Not good scene for people in early 20s, for sure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thai Stellar&lt;/strong&gt; – Prior to visiting NASA Johnson Space Center, we got food. It’s standard Thai cuisine, very cheap (you can get meal under $10). When they ask you for spice level, note that level 4 (what most my table got) was not spicy at all, for people who like and don’t mind spicy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rocket Park at NASA Johnson Center&lt;/strong&gt; – Seeing the rockets made me have a greater respect for the human mind. Literally, I cannot comprehend the inputs required to enable humans to send a person to outer space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bucc-ee’s&lt;/strong&gt; – This is like a Walmart gas station that is a unique experience in Texas. It just has lots of gas stations, car wash stations, huge store. So many people recommended seeing it, and we did. I was frustrated seeing all the plastic and single-use plastics available here. Because of my interests in sustainability, health, and nutrition, I was not impressed by the place. However, I do think it’s worth to stop by if it’s on your way to a destination though; interesting take on gas station.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was a good trip overall. Even though it was only a 48 hour trip, it felt like a really long time, like a whole week. Work seems so far away. I think the feeling that it was a long trip means I really lived in the present and was enjoying the moments. I’m still thinking about the cachapas and the sauce from the camarones (shrimp) we ordered; freaking delicious. I want more. :P&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="adventures" /><summary type="html">A couple cointerns and I made a road trip to Houston this weekend. After work on Friday, we picked up our rental car and peaced out of Austin.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smiling is magic.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/smiles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smiling is magic." /><published>2019-07-13T04:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T04:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/smiles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/smiles.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a good Saturday. I got a much-needed good night’s sleep, no alarm to wake me up. Put in a little workout in the morning and off to the farmers’ market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin is cool in that it has municipal composting. My apartment doesn’t have composting, but I can make a trip to my preferred grocery stores and compost my food scraps there. I collect my week’s compost in my freezer, and it was piling up, so I made a trip to Whole Foods to dispose of my compost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, my bro called me, which was a really nice surprise! We talked for an hour, where he filled me in on his first week at his new job (exciting)! We had a good sibling chat, while I enjoyed the views of families and individuals enjoying the park next to the downtown farmers’ market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a bus day today, aka I got a 24 hour bus pass to travel around Austin. This was mainly due to the very hot weather and my need to get to places faster than it would take me to walk to places. I’m not sure what was going on though, but so many people smiled at me today. I think it might be because I have a natural tendency to smile at people who I make eye contact with. And people’s natural instinct is to smile back. However, I noticed it a lot more today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made me feel extra good to be smiled at. If you’re curious as to why I have a natural tendency to smile a lot and to people, it’s because it feels good to be smiled at, and it makes others smile. When I was little, I liked people who smiled at me. And wanting others to like me, I practiced smiling at other people, genuinely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned here in Austin is that it’s nice to say ‘thank you’ to the bus drivers. It seems obvious but so few people do it. When I took my first bus trip in Austin, I saw a guy say ‘thank you’ to the bus driver when he got off. And in my head, I was like, “Wow, that’s so nice!” So I’ve been doing that too now. When I get off, I’ll look at the bus driver via their mirror, say thank you (and smile if I remember to, I’m not super conscious when I smile anymore), maybe wave, and get off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also say ‘hi’ to the bus driver and smile every time I get on. Today, every single bus driver smiled back and said ‘hi’ to me. It made me feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found an African fashion show to attend, and there, I made eye contact with this little girl. I smiled, and her face lit up, and she smiled back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hahaha, these aren’t really exciting stories, but as I am writing about them, it just makes me smile and feel good. There’s lots of positive energy that comes from this small exchange. I had more smile exchanges with vendors at the farmers’ market today, other attendees of the African fashion show, and people in my apartment building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I’m dedicating to being alone and getting a lot more content editing done for my app. I had a little too much excitement this week and need a break from fully engaging with people. And I have to say, this weekend is the best weekend I’ve had so far. It feels good to be alone, to do my own thing and have small moments of positivity with so many strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was more a brain dump and my day’s update, haha. The main takeaway though: smiling is magic, try it. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">Today was a good Saturday. I got a much-needed good night’s sleep, no alarm to wake me up. Put in a little workout in the morning and off to the farmers’ market.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Food waste bothers me.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/food-waste.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Food waste bothers me." /><published>2019-07-13T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/food-waste</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/13/food-waste.html">&lt;p&gt;When I see people not finish their food (at restaurants, parties, anywhere), I get a bit upset. I’m conflicted though because sometimes I wonder, what right do I have to tell people to finish their food when they’re full, don’t like the food, or just don’t want anymore of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What frustrates me about food waste is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) the resources invested in making that food is wasted. The water used to grow and wash the food. The time, energy, and effort that people put into growing, transporting, processing, and cooking the food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) there are hungry people in the world who would be so happy and grateful to eat your leftovers. Yet, they can’t. And these people who aren’t finishing their food often don’t seem to appreciate or understand how fortunate they are to have food in front of them. They don’t show any remorse over the waste of food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) most places and people do not dispose of their food waste properly. They often just toss it onto the trash, where the food will rot in landfills, releasing large amounts of methane that get trapped as more trash piles on top. This is problematic for our environment, because this trapping warms the atmosphere, thereby contributing to climate change in a not-so-beneficial way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And btw, reducing food waste is #3 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drawdown.org/solutions/food/reduced-food-waste&quot;&gt;Project Drawdown’s&lt;/a&gt; list of climate solutions. Project Drawdown is a non-profit that curated a list of top 100 actions that people can take to effectively tackle climate change, based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drawdown.org/frequently-asked-questions&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; conducted around the world on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom raised me to eat every last grain of rice out of my bowl. No waste. When I was in India for a summer, I saw another level of “cleaning your plate”. People would use their chapati and/or hands to get every last grain of rice and drop of sauce. I’ve come to adopt a similar eating habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I know I am going to an event where food is available, I will bring my own reusable food container in case there are any leftovers. So, no food waste and no to-go packaging waste. Oftentimes, I’ll eat everything on my plate though. (I know my apetite well and how much food I can take in.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my friends. They will have me finish their leftovers or I will have them finish mine. But with people I’m not that close with, it is an odd request to make sometimes. Depending on how hungry, how bothered I am, how good the food is, how courageous I am in that moment, I will ask if I can finish their food. Sometimes, I leave it, say nothing, and leave bothered. I don’t want to be people’s “trashcan”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying people should do anything. I just wish people would be mindful of the impact of their actions and choices (in this case, with respect to food waste).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">When I see people not finish their food (at restaurants, parties, anywhere), I get a bit upset. I’m conflicted though because sometimes I wonder, what right do I have to tell people to finish their food when they’re full, don’t like the food, or just don’t want anymore of it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop, fake meat ain’t for plant-based eaters.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/10/fake-meat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop, fake meat ain't for plant-based eaters." /><published>2019-07-10T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/10/fake-meat</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/10/fake-meat.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preachin’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a little heated about this topic. Call me extra or strict, but my feelings are valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, company provided fried chicken + mac and cheese + fries + mixed greens salad from Happy Chicks for lunch. The main vegetarian/vegan option was vegan fried chicken and vegetarian mac and cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t speak for everyone; these are my opinions. As someone who voluntarily chooses to eat a plant-based diet (I define as no animal meat; little to no dairy products; lots of whole vegetables and fruits from farms; and lots ancient grains, legumes, and beans.), I have no interest in eating fake meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not alone in this; I have talked to other people who choose to follow a vegan and vegetarian diet. We once talked about the Impossible burger. An acquaintance was vegetarian for like 6 years; she thought she would try the Impossible burger since it was such a huge deal. After a bite, she literally spit it all out because it tasted and felt too similar to meat for her (whether that is accurate is relative. She hadn’t had anything meat-like textured for so long that anything remotely close to meat texture would seem meat-like.) We choose to not eat animal products, so what’s the point of trying to imitate it and pursuing it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodrevolution.org/blog/plant-based-meat-alternatives/&quot;&gt;fake meat is often made with refined oils (processed the hell out of), GMO soy (large traces of pesticides, herbicides, and insecticides, especially glyphosate, an active ingredient in RoundUp, a common weed killer), and additives that have little nutrition&lt;/a&gt;. No thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fake meat, in my opinion, is mainly geared towards serving the meat eaters in the world, to help them reduce their meat consumption for the sake of mitigating climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I was hella disappointed in the lunch offered today. What about the vegetarian mac and cheese and fries? A company called “Happy Chicks” is ironic considering how many “chicks” they kill to do business, and I highly doubt those “chicks” were well taken care of when they were alive. From a moral and ethical standpoint, no thanks. I have no interest in eating anything you have to serve. I’m objectively speaking a healthy conscious eater, so I doubt their fries and mac and cheese were of anything worthwhile to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just brought my own lunch to eat today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A snippet of my journey to shifting my mindset to eating less meat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see why the food is so enticing. The entire food area smelled of fried foods, and it did smell good. The food is all deep fried such that there’s lots of crunch; I can see, smell, and understand the appeal. However, this is all about mindset and the environment in which we grew up in and how it has impacted our view of what is considered “good” food. And I’m at a point where I eat for nutrition and nourishment. I (most of the time) know what I am putting in my body and make sure it is good for me and my environment. I’m not perfect; sometimes, I pursue ignorance (oftentimes for sweets, I’m a sucker for a tasty cheesecake).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following a plant-based diet for about 3 months now. I care for the environment; however, diet change was something I was reluctant to do; it was a bit hard to transition. I grew up eating lots of chicken, fish, and pork; it’s part of many Chinese dishes. However, as I was reading more about the impact of &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodprint.org/issues/raising-animals-industrial-system/&quot;&gt;raising animals in an industrial system&lt;/a&gt; and knowing that I want to live by the values I talk about, I chose to reduce my meat consumption slightly. I chose chicken over pork and beef. I also opted for smaller meat portions in a meal. Inside though, I knew I could be doing so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My commitment journey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I saw this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nUnJQWO4YJY&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;, and it was the tipping point for me to 100% commit to cutting out meat from my diet. The logic is there, and I knew it was my mentality that was holding me back from not eating any meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with cutting beef out of my diet. It was an easy start because beef isn’t a significant component of my diet. Now, it’s been 2 years my diet is almost beef-free. I did accidentally eat it a couple times, mistaking a dish had pork when it actually had beef, but it’s all good. I know mistakes happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the process of weaning off pork and chicken. It’s hard at home because my parents cook it so often, but now that I’m on my own this summer and I am in control of my purchasing choices, it is very much easier. I haven’t completely cut it out of my diet. I’ve cut about 95% of it out of my diet though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, when I go out to eat, I will choose a plant-based dish. So, when I’m out, my diet is 100% meat free because I know most places I eat at will not source pasture-raised certified humane meats. However, I have bought a pasture-raised certified humane organic chicken from the farmers’ market to make a soup for the “healing” properties after my period; it’s something my mom makes for me. I am okay with this right now because I at least know I am supporting local and ethical practices in raising animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big adjustment to cutting meat out from my diet is learning how to cook and eat more vegetables to make up for the lack of meat in most of my meals. I used be hungry very often because I wasn’t proportionately swapping the vegetables for meat. Practice, commitment, and patience have been critical in helping me get to where I am now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’ve noticed changes in my body. I can’t 100% attribute these changes to just my diet change because I’ve changed a lot both in mindset and lifestyle in the past couple years. But I know for sure (gotta take my word for it and the numerous research studies out there) that eating less meat has contributed to empowering my body with more natural good energy. I feel good in my body, I love what I eat and what I do, and I’m just enjoying life right now. And I know I’m not contributing as much to the factors that contribute to climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not trying to convert you to not eat meat. I’m a supporter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodprint.org/eating-sustainably/eating-meat-sustainably/&quot;&gt;eating less meat and better meat&lt;/a&gt;. My main goal with this post is to release the frustration I have about people’s assumption that “Oh, we have vegan meats available so you can eat too!” and share a little bit of my journey of including less meat in my diet. It wasn’t super easy, but I’m determined and I’ve made a significant amount of progress; I’m proud to be where I’m at.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">Preachin’</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My life in Austin.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/07/Austin-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My life in Austin." /><published>2019-07-07T04:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-07T04:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/07/Austin-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lifestyle/2019/07/07/Austin-life.html">&lt;p&gt;As of 7/7/2019, I am 5 weeks into my summer here in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have I been spending my time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work M-F around 9am-6pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My morning routine involves meditating with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wakingup.com/&quot;&gt;Waking Up App&lt;/a&gt; by Sam Harris, bathroom stuff, and then I’ll make breakfast and prep lunch. And off I walk to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my walk back to apartment after work, I’ll often call my mom, brother (main one recently), or a friend to chat with. My apartment has a swimming pool that I swim in about 3x a week after work (best workout – can’t feel my sweat, get exercise, not sunny cause the height of the apartment blocks the sun). I’ll cook dinner, usually some kind of stir fry of veggies mixed with black beans, lentils, oatmeal, buckwheat groats, or brown rice. Finish meal with a piece of fruit (loving the summer stone fruits right now). Work on app project and maybe call up a friend or my brother. Music has always been on for at least some part of my day, especially when in my apartment (cause it gets quiet and still sometimes), so I get some dancing (and maybe a little bit of singing) in on the daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My weekend routine includes shopping at farmers’ market for groceries; doing something new or exploring a new part of Austin; reflecting and journaling; meeting with my app project team; working on app project; and hanging out with at least one coworker. This has been a consistent routine each weekend so far. Usually Saturday is my adventure and explore day, and Sunday is my stay-at-apartment-to-work-day. Either way, I make sure I get out of the apartment for at least an hour each day. I usually make a trip to a grocery store (used to be Whole Foods, but now switching to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheatsville.coop/&quot;&gt;Wheatsville Co-op&lt;/a&gt;) if I’ve been in my apartment all day. An aside: I love grocery shopping, because I love food and I love seeing more organic, fair trade, local options available in stores. I don’t like any other shopping (e.g. clothes, malls, cars, house). To me, they’re a waste of time; I’d rather do other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s a list of what I think are interesting things I’ve done so far (not in any particular order):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nightlife in Red River Cultural District (Cheer Up Charlie’s drag show + Stubb’s LANY concert) and Rainey St. –&amp;gt; Accidentally got a little drunk for first time(!) I was fine, just little off balanced, but I had supportive co-interns dancing and keeping an eye out for me. ;) It was a fun night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tried out a few fitness classes: Ro Fitness (good cardio), Lagree Studio (kicked my butt, that was tough but good workout), City Surf Fitness (ehhh, wasn’t fan of instructor and not great workout)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SFC Downtown Farmers’ Market!! I look forward to this every Saturday; it’s where I get 95% of my groceries and actually found a local jeweler who made very beautiful simple everyday rings (I got 3).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whole Foods Market cafe. In need of getting out of my apartment, I ventured here to work on the weekends (for app project). Interesting moment here was getting into a conversation with a stranger for like 2 hours after he asked to borrow my Android phone charger. We talked about a lot of things: career, family, identity, childhood, food, travels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gokarting at Circuit of the Americas, which I wrote a little bit on in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://j-fang.github.io/adventures/2019/07/02/lean-into-that-fear.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barton Creek Greenbelt trail – nature. beautiful. go see it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fredericksburg + peach picking. It was a hot day trip with my coworkers. We ambled through random shops. I wished to have seen more, but at least half the people I went with didn’t have similar shopping tastes as me, so I didn’t want to hold them back. :P&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wander through the streets and neighborhoods of East Austin, Burnet Road, Downtown, S Lamar, South Congress, West Campus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attended a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookpeople.com/&quot;&gt;BookPeople&lt;/a&gt; Well-Read Black Girl book club event and an author event with Elaine Welteroth, associated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spent hours at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookpeople.com/&quot;&gt;BookPeople&lt;/a&gt; to read books.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve actually stayed consistent with catching up with calling family and friends. Will call at least 3 different people each week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I like it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty satisfied with my summer so far (outside of work. inside of work is another story that I will touch on later). I’m doing the things I want to do: spending time with people who make me smile and laugh; staying in touch with my family and friends; working on a cool project that I’m really excited to launch later this year; exploring a new city at a comfortable pace; going to my local farmers’ markets; managing to feed myself well and exercise regularly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">As of 7/7/2019, I am 5 weeks into my summer here in Austin.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Local transport rocks.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/07/local-transport-rocks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Local transport rocks." /><published>2019-07-07T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-07T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/07/local-transport-rocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/07/local-transport-rocks.html">&lt;p&gt;I discovered the Austin bus system!! Now my exploration zone has expanded by a 5 mile radius. I’m so freaking excited and happy about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I walked everywhere, and I enjoyed it; it’s how I travel and discover new places when I am in a new city. I’m willing to walk 40 minutes to get to a destination, given time permits. However, in the first few weeks I’ve been here, I kind of maxed out seeing all that I am interested in the Austin West Campus and downtown area, given the heat and humidity of the summer. I also adventured a bit of East Austin and South Congress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t like taking Ubers or Lyfts because 1) I’m frugal and don’t like spending so much money on transportation and 2) I don’t like traveling with car. I don’t see or experience much of a new place that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the bus, it’s $2.50 for a 24 hour pass, and it will take me close to any destination I’ve wanted to go to so far. They have an app that makes it super convenient to purchase and use tickets. Google Maps has been immensely helpful in figuring out what buses to take and how to get to location X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus has enabled me to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) stroll through the Barton Creek Greenbelt trails (to spend some time in nature and outdoors)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) shop leisurely through Burnet Road (and discover Wheatesville Coop, a local grocery store that I am excited to now support)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) shorten my morning farmers’ market trips, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) venture through S Lamar where there are many yummy restaurants that I want to try out one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Austin adventures await :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="adventures" /><summary type="html">I discovered the Austin bus system!! Now my exploration zone has expanded by a 5 mile radius. I’m so freaking excited and happy about this.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lean into the fear.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/02/lean-into-that-fear.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lean into the fear." /><published>2019-07-02T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/02/lean-into-that-fear</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/2019/07/02/lean-into-that-fear.html">&lt;p&gt;My brother was always the risk taker. He would pick fake fights with family friends. On his first time on the ice rink, he skated as if he were a natural. He was the only one in the family to dare ride a roller coaster, and because my dad’s love for him was greater than his fear, my dad rode with him (after that ride in Universal Studios, both were like, “that was too scary…”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, played it safe. I was obedient, followed my elder’s rules and instructions to a T. I remember. Once on a field trip to a museum, the chaperone of my group instructed us to follow her so we wouldn’t get lost. What that means is keep an eye on the group and stick with it. For me, I just follow-the-leadered her, trailing her into the bathroom to wash her hands and as she meandered while we were waiting for entry into the museum. She laughed and told me she didn’t mean I literally had to follow her, and I remember thinking to myself, “You said to follow you though…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think part of my personality was due to my parents working all the time. Every time they dropped off my brother and I at my grandma’s house, they would remind us to love each other and watch out for each other. Knowing the stress my parents carried to afford our humble lifestyle, I took those words to heart, and I assumed a more parental role over my brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has hindered me in many ways, some of which I still struggle with right now. However, one thing that I have taken away from these experiences is to lean into my fears. I’ve been presented with opportunities that sound very exciting. My immediate response is, “I want to do that!” However, when I am actually given the opportunity to do it, I tell myself, “I can’t. I’m scared.” But then I see my brother do it, and I’m like, “Come on. If he can do it, I should be able to do it too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no pivoting moment where I realized this. It’s been a slow change I’ve been tackling since high school. And I’ve noticed it more recently in my conversations with people and the activities I’ve pursued in my summer life at Austin, TX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I went gokarting with a crew of Cloudflare employees and co-interns. I had a lot of fun through the heat and sweat. First, I felt so cool driving the gokart. How can you not when you wear such a large helmet and drive at seemingly high speeds with loud car engine noises? And when you pass other racers (that happened only twice for me)? That’s the best part, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also discovered another world. The technique and strategy to braking and gassing the gokart requires skill! My ego got the best of me after a good 2nd race (we raced 3 races in total), and I spun out way too many times by gassing too much on my 3rd race, placing dead last (very humbling).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I noticed in my interactions with the group was that 3 out of the 5 people asked me if I had fun. They didn’t ask that question to anyone else, not that I heard of at least. I don’t know what that means. My hypothesis is that 1) I’m a female, 2) I was not very talkative (that’s in my nature, but I don’t think I talked significantly less compared to the others), 3) it was coincidence, or 4) some other reason. I was very aware that I was the only female in the group. My mom noticed it immediately too when I sent her a photo of the crew. I don’t think it’s worth thinking too much about, but it did bother me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What provoked me to write on this is 1) to share my adventure (since this category is lacking so far) and 2) a cointern had made a side comment on how I’m risk taking (I forgot his exact word choice). And I just wanted to share: my immediate response to the gokarting event was like, “heck yea, I want to do it! sounds fun.” But my mind was telling me, “it seems kinda scary to drive at 55mph though…” I didn’t respond to the group chat until a week after when they were finalizing ticket purchases when I told myself, “Being scared is not a good reason not to do something.” So I let them know I wanted to join. I don’t self-describe myself as a risk taker, but I am intentional about accepting opportunities that are available to me that I’m interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t lean into everything though. One thing I won’t do is bungee jump, because I have no interest in doing so (not because I’m scared. I am scared, but I would push myself to do it if I had any interest.) It’s not easy to lean in. It takes intention, determination, and consciousness, but it’s all worth it in the end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="adventures" /><summary type="html">My brother was always the risk taker. He would pick fake fights with family friends. On his first time on the ice rink, he skated as if he were a natural. He was the only one in the family to dare ride a roller coaster, and because my dad’s love for him was greater than his fear, my dad rode with him (after that ride in Universal Studios, both were like, “that was too scary…”).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What we don’t want to pay for.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/06/24/what-we-dont-want-to-pay-for.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What we don't want to pay for." /><published>2019-06-24T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/06/24/what-we-dont-want-to-pay-for</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/06/24/what-we-dont-want-to-pay-for.html">&lt;p&gt;I found a book club at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookpeople.com/&quot;&gt;BookPeople&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookpeopleblog.com/2019/03/28/new-well-read-black-girl-book-club/&quot;&gt;Well Read Black Girl&lt;/a&gt;. I got a vibe 
that this book club would touch upon female empowerment, which I’m a huge advocate for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had their meeting today, and the book of choice for this meeting is “The Source of Self-Regard” by Toni Morrison. I’ve heard her name mentioned a few times in my life, so I recognized it as a “big” name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started reading this book two days before the book club meeting, I did not expect something
so dense. I had to reread almost every paragraph a few times to really just understand what the words were. The meaning sunk in sometimes, and sometimes not. It didn’t help that I had things on my mind, which kept distracting me from Toni’s words. (Aside: did you know her Chloe? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notablebiographies.com/Mo-Ni/Morrison-Toni.html&quot;&gt;Chloe Anthony Wofford&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the small nuggets that did penetrate the depths of my brain, I did get a small glimpse of Toni’s brilliance, the truths she speaks of that is so relevant to the societal problems we see today. And I was conflicted. How can the work of such an incredibly smart woman be so inaccessible to everyday people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hear me out before you jump to conclusions about that question. Let me unpack that first. I didn’t get to finish the book as I tried to cram as much as I could before the book club meeting. FYI, cramming is a very poor method to read this book and to retain and understand meaning and messages that Toni conveys through her words. In the quick glimpses of the gems of Toni’s words, my mind was like, “Wow, that is so true. I wish more people could read this and understand it from Toni’s perspective.” Yet, I knew that I am not representative of the general young population. Most people my age would not spend the time to read this book nor choose it over another probably. A major part of it is because it’s not an easy read. How can this book be made more accessible to “everyday” people? It’s not fair for Toni to have to change her language, change her way of expression to appease “everyday” people, especially when even if it were an easy read, I don’t know if that many people would or could appreciate Toni’s words. But that’s one question that I had coming into the book club meeting: where is the balance in maintaining an author’s authenticity of their words and making that authenticity accessible to people? I didn’t have an answer and didn’t know how to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My takeaway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple attendees attempted to address my question. From their responses, I learned, realized, and have now come to believe that it’s not the author or artist’s responsbility to compromise their work to engage a larger population of people. It’s the reader’s responsibility to appreciate the artists’ work and efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an analogy that someone said which effectively captures this idea. An author and artist (authors are also artists) will work their butt off climbing up the mountain (producing their works of art). They welcome you up the mountain (by sharing their works through books, music, poetry, paintings, photography, and many more forms of art) to join them (to learn from another’s point of view), but it is NOT the author’s responsibility to pull you up the mountain to get to the top (compromising or unnecessarily simplifying their work to satisfy others). It is your responsibility as a reader to do your part and get up there yourself. Of course, there is some balance of writing in a way that captures a reader’s attention, but that’s besides the point of this lesson I learned today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not meant to be easy for a reader. And I think that’s a lesson I didn’t learn well in school.
Middle and high school was all about getting the themes and summaries through CliffNotes, because 
“I had no idea” what the deeper meaning of this book is about. I never challenged myself to think
harder, to spend the time pondering an idea for longer timeframes, to revisit words and text and
see them with a refreshed perspective. I conditioned myself to be spoonfed. I feel kind of 
ashamed and embarrassed about it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of working to meet an author where they’re at (in this mountain journey) extends to other artists too. Books, instrumental music, paintings, choreography, photographs, sculptures, singing, plays, operas. (These are just some examples.) I’ve been guilty of thinking, this book costs $30, what!? This ticket costs $500!? No way am I paying for this. Yet, people are willing to pay $900 for a new phone, thousands of dollars for a new computer. I’m guilty of it (the latter, not the former. I will not pay more than $400 for a phone as of now. Who knows though, I may give in in a few years…I hope not. :P)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are valid reasons why technology costs more and people are more willing to pay for them. But
the main idea I’m getting at here is the society I’ve grown up in has conditioned me to believe in values that are misaligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t recognize the struggles, the emotions, the hardship that comes with writing and creating. It’s not easy!! (Let’s be real, I could never drop an album like Beyonce or even write a children’s song for a TV show like Sesame Street or Blue’s Clues). And this is partially due to the way media portrays people and how often they talk about success stories over people’s imperfect and difficult road to “success”. Many of us don’t understand the sweat, tears, and challenges that artists face and overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A challenge to myself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am now, thinking about what I can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m going to give “The Source of Self-Regard” another several attempts. It’s a book you gotta read and reread many more than several more times to extract all the nuggets of wisdom from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I ever encounter a difficult book to read, I will pause, recognize that, and not give up trying to read it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next time I engage with art through whatever medium (listening, seeing, touching, doing), I’m going to try to think about the artists and what they could have gone through to create that piece. Whether it’s good or bad art, it’s often not an easy thing to do. I’m going to intentionally spend a moment to recognize someone for their efforts to produce something new. And if I think it’s real good and worth keeping a copy of, I will support them as directly as I can (e.g. local bookstore &amp;gt; Amazon. I can also afford it right now. Compensation as a PM at a well-reputed tech company is higher than I ever expected to earn myself). We need more people trying to do something as opposed to nothing. I also believe that the world will benefit with more cultural and art appreciation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ponderings" /><summary type="html">I found a book club at BookPeople called Well Read Black Girl. I got a vibe that this book club would touch upon female empowerment, which I’m a huge advocate for.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We don’t eat enough vegetables.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/06/18/we-dont-eat-enough-vegetables.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We don't eat enough vegetables." /><published>2019-06-18T03:05:25-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T03:05:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/06/18/we-dont-eat-enough-vegetables</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ponderings/2019/06/18/we-dont-eat-enough-vegetables.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me + Plant-based diet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end or beginning of each new big event of my life (e.g. starting new school semester, ending a semester, starting an internship), I reflect. I think about what went well, what didn’t, what my goals are for the next phase of my year so I can live it better. And one thing I’ve been gradually changing is my diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m transitioning to eating a more plant-based diet, which focuses on: vegetables, fruits, grains, nuts, and seeds. Do not interchange “plant-based” and “vegan”. There are so many vegan products out there now (e.g. Oreos, marshmallows, cookies), but they don’t fall into a plant-based diet. A plant-based diet means whole foods that come from nature and aren’t heavily processed and inadvertently, packaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in a Chinese cultural environment, ½ of my parents’ cooking were always fish and meats. Having a huge interest in environmental sustainability and health, I knew, generally speaking, that it’s better to not eat so many meats and fish, but I didn’t know exactly why. I couldn’t tell you what exactly are the benefits, except that it’s “good”. So, with an intention to eat more plant-based and this lack of knowledge, I dove into learning more about nutrition for two weeks in May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What stood out most to me in my research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The act of eating meat isn’t bad. Hundreds of years ago, people around the world ate animals, but they didn’t experience the high levels of chronic disease that people do today. The problem today is the way that the livestock industry has grown. The demand for meat has increased so dramatically, that farm businesses are taking shortcuts in order to increase their profit margins. As a consequence, animals are not treated humanely, which impacts the animals’ health and well-being. When we consume these animals, the biology of their health transfers into our bodies, which isn’t good for our health.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have a lot to say about cooking and my experience, especially learning how to cook vegetables. But I’ll save that for another post that I will link here in the future. The main idea is that following a plant-based diet isn’t the hard part. I know what I should more of and should eat less of. The hard part is really learning how to change how my mind and taste buds react to vegetables and how to cook vegetables and make them tasty. Without a determination to commit to a plant-based diet, it’s easy to default back to sugary snacks and eat what I’m used to eating.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here’s my summary of the importance of eating those &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drfuhrman.com/get-started/eat-to-live-blog/62/the-healthiest-anti-cancer-foods-g-bombs&quot;&gt;GBOMBS&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GBOMBS contain fiber that makes meals feel more satiating, so I won’t feel like I have to snack so much. Fiber also enables good bacteria in our intestines to grow, which boosts the biodiversity of our gut and enables our body to better protect against any attacks or imbalances.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Meat, poultry, fish, eggs, and dairy products (e.g. milk, yogurt, cheese) don’t have any fiber in them.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GBOMBS have high anti-inflammatory effects, which makes our bodies feel better. Inflammation in the body means an increased blood flow to areas of injury, infection, or perceived invasion of foreign substances. This results in bloating, aches, and pains.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;B12 is a vitamin that’s vital for DNA synthesis, maintaining our nervous systems, and red blood cell production. People tend to think that you can only get vitamin B12 from eating meat. This is because vitamin B12 is often found in animal muscles. &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodrevolution.org/blog/supplements-vegetarians-vegans-plant-based/?utm_campaign=frn19&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=email-automated&amp;amp;utm_content=5444&amp;amp;utm_term=existing-email-list&amp;amp;email=&amp;amp;firstname=Friend&amp;amp;lastname=&quot;&gt;However, microorganisms living in soil and water make B12, not animals.&lt;/a&gt; Animals, like cows, eat the grass or crops with B12 producing organisms that cling to the soil particles in the plant’s roots. However, because our water system is heavily treated and we transport food for such long distances, eating just plants won’t provide most people enough B12 for their bodies. A solution is eating B12 supplements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doing this research made me feel empowered and more confident. Because I can now explain why eating plants is better for our bodies and I have this knowledge backing my actions. There’s so much more I learned and took notes on (cause I can’t remember all that), but they get into more details that don’t feel as important to discuss right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**Please note: the above summary is not well credited or sourced. I will do so when and if I feel like doing so. I may have misrepresented some information and could be incorrect; that is my own fault and I take credit for it. However, I don’t want these flaws to prevent me from pursuing the purpose of my writing: to practice expressing my thoughts, so I shall continue on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear: I am not perfect. I still eat meat (except beef, which I’ve completely cut out of my diet for the past year and a half). I do snack on packaged and processed sweets here and there and other foods that are not considered plant-based or “healthy”. And I’m fine with that. I don’t view life to be a strict “I have to do this” and “I can’t do that”. I think all that matters is that I am continuously improving and making progress towards my personal goal, and I am doing that. I’m actually really proud of how far I’ve come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I stand by the claim of my title&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haha, it’s funny, I still haven’t gotten to the story I wanted to share that inspired the title of this article. About a month ago, I stayed with my brother for a few days before his graduation. At that time, I had already made my summer goal of eating a more plant-based diet and learning how to cook tastier vegetable dishes. Those few days with my brother captured the opposite of my intentions for the summer. We ate out almost every meal those days, eating a wide variety of Asian cuisines (my favorite).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What shocked me was how little vegetables there were offered on the menus. We ate at a local Indian restaurant that was vegetarian only, which had the most vegetable dishes to offer. However, the ramen and sushi places we went to basically offered: noodles/rice and meat (i.e. pork, chicken, fish). I got a vegetarian ramen, which thank you California, had a decent serving of vegetables. But, my brother got a non-vegetarian dish that had only seaweed strips as “vegetables” on top. Just because someone orders a meat-based dish doesn’t mean we should be stripping it of vegetables! The sushi places we went to made me even sadder. Their vegetable offerings were American salads made of iceberg lettuce (one of the most useless and nutritionless vegetables to exist).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made me realize how little attention and value people place on vegetables, culturally here in the US. I don’t have enough experience to make such a statement for other countries, many for which I think this statement still holds true. This is when I realized that most people don’t eat enough vegetables. We don’t place enough value on them. We don’t understand the importance and value they provide to our health. We don’t understand or appreciate the efforts required to grow nutrient-dense produce for people. And many don’t understand the long term effects of including more fresh, local, organic, seasonal, non-GMO veggies in their diets. There’s also a dilemma of making this type of food accessible for everyone; education and access are huge factors in this equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation isn’t hopeless though. There are many people like &lt;a href=&quot;http://ronfinley.com/&quot;&gt;Ron Finley&lt;/a&gt; and organizations like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consciouskitchen.org/&quot;&gt;The Conscious Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://urbanrootsatx.org/&quot;&gt;Urban Roots&lt;/a&gt;, who are doing something. I am doing something too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read to this point, thank you, I appreciate your interest and time to listen to me. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s a quote that I’ve found to be very empowering and true to how I try live my day to day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am only one, but I am one. I cannot do everything, but I can do something. And because I can’t do everything, I will not refuse to do the something I can do.” -Edward Everett Hale&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ponderings" /><summary type="html">Me + Plant-based diet</summary></entry></feed>